[
    {
        "question": "For I know the plans I have for you, declares the LORD, plans for welfare(1) and not for evil, to give you a future and a hope. Footnotes (1) 29:11 Or *peace* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 29:11",
        "rank": "29"
    },
    {
        "question": "The heart is deceitful above all things, and desperately sick; who can understand it? (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 17:9",
        "rank": "231"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cBehold, the days are coming, declares the LORD, when I will make a new covenant with the house of Israel and the house of Judah, (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 31:31",
        "rank": "355"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hear the word of the LORD, O house of Jacob, and all the clans of the house of Israel. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 2:4",
        "rank": "657"
    },
    {
        "question": "Now the word of the LORD came to me, saying, (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 1:4",
        "rank": "675"
    },
    {
        "question": "Call to me and I will answer you, and will tell you great and hidden things that you have not known. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 33:3",
        "rank": "691"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cBefore I formed you in the womb I knew you, and before you were born I consecrated you; I appointed you a prophet to the nations.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 1:5",
        "rank": "724"
    },
    {
        "question": "Thus says the LORD: \u201cStand by the roads, and look, and ask for the ancient paths, where the good way is; and walk in it, and find rest for your souls. But they said, \u2018We will not walk in it.\u2019 (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 6:16",
        "rank": "1,163"
    },
    {
        "question": "It came also in the days of Jehoiakim the son of Josiah, king of Judah, and until the end of the eleventh year of Zedekiah, the son of Josiah, king of Judah, until the captivity of Jerusalem in the fifth month. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 1:3",
        "rank": "1,201"
    },
    {
        "question": "Do not be afraid of them, for I am with you to deliver you, declares the LORD.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 1:8",
        "rank": "1,260"
    },
    {
        "question": "Then I said, \u201cAh, Lord GOD! Behold, I do not know how to speak, for I am only a youth.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 1:6",
        "rank": "1,297"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cBehold, the days are coming, declares the LORD, when I will raise up for David a righteous Branch, and he shall reign as king and deal wisely, and shall execute justice and righteousness in the land. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 23:5",
        "rank": "1,418"
    },
    {
        "question": "You will seek me and find me, when you seek me with all your heart. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 29:13",
        "rank": "1,433"
    },
    {
        "question": "the LORD appeared to him(1) from far away. I have loved you with an everlasting love; therefore I have continued my faithfulness to you. Footnotes (1) 31:3 Septuagint; Hebrew *me* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 31:3",
        "rank": "1,460"
    },
    {
        "question": "Israel was holy to the LORD, the firstfruits of his harvest. All who ate of it incurred guilt; disaster came upon them, declares the LORD.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 2:3",
        "rank": "1,502"
    },
    {
        "question": "Thus says the LORD: \u201cCursed is the man who trusts in man and makes flesh his strength,(1) whose heart turns away from the LORD. Footnotes (1) 17:5 Hebrew *arm* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 17:5",
        "rank": "1,556"
    },
    {
        "question": "For this is the covenant that I will make with the house of Israel after those days, declares the LORD: I will put my law within them, and I will write it on their hearts. And I will be their God, and they shall be my people. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 31:33",
        "rank": "1,660"
    },
    {
        "question": "Your words were found, and I ate them, and your words became to me a joy and the delight of my heart, for I am called by your name, O LORD, God of hosts. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 15:16",
        "rank": "2,357"
    },
    {
        "question": "And the word of the LORD came to me, saying, \u201cJeremiah, what do you see?\u201d And I said, \u201cI see an almond(1) branch.\u201d Footnotes (1) 1:11 *Almond* sounds like the Hebrew for *watching* (compare verse 12) (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 1:11",
        "rank": "2,463"
    },
    {
        "question": "But the LORD is the true God; he is the living God and the everlasting King. At his wrath the earth quakes, and the nations cannot endure his indignation. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 10:10",
        "rank": "2,494"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cBehold, you trust in deceptive words to no avail. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 7:8",
        "rank": "2,597"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cBlessed is the man who trusts in the LORD, whose trust is the LORD. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 17:7",
        "rank": "2,631"
    },
    {
        "question": "But the LORD said to me, \u201cDo not say, \u2018I am only a youth\u2019; for to all to whom I send you, you shall go, and whatever I command you, you shall speak. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 1:7",
        "rank": "2,651"
    },
    {
        "question": "The word that came to Jeremiah from the LORD: (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 18:1",
        "rank": "2,688"
    },
    {
        "question": "Then the LORD put out his hand and touched my mouth. And the LORD said to me, \u201cBehold, I have put my words in your mouth. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 1:9",
        "rank": "2,724"
    },
    {
        "question": "Have you not just now called to me, \u2018My father, you are the friend of my youth\u2014 (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 3:4",
        "rank": "2,793"
    },
    {
        "question": "Thus shall you say to them: \u201cThe gods who did not make the heavens and the earth shall perish from the earth and from under the heavens.\u201d(1) Footnotes (1) 10:11 This verse is in Aramaic (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 10:11",
        "rank": "2,859"
    },
    {
        "question": "Thus says the LORD: \u201cLet not the wise man boast in his wisdom, let not the mighty man boast in his might, let not the rich man boast in his riches, (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 9:23",
        "rank": "2,902"
    },
    {
        "question": "Let those be put to shame who persecute me, but let me not be put to shame; let them be dismayed, but let me not be dismayed; bring upon them the day of disaster; destroy them with double destruction! (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 17:18",
        "rank": "2,943"
    },
    {
        "question": "See, I have set you this day over nations and over kingdoms, to pluck up and to break down, to destroy and to overthrow, to build and to plant.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 1:10",
        "rank": "2,944"
    },
    {
        "question": "The word of the LORD came to me a second time, saying, \u201cWhat do you see?\u201d And I said, \u201cI see a boiling pot, facing away from the north.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 1:13",
        "rank": "3,015"
    },
    {
        "question": "not like the covenant that I made with their fathers on the day when I took them by the hand to bring them out of the land of Egypt, my covenant that they broke, though I was their husband, declares the LORD. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 31:32",
        "rank": "3,134"
    },
    {
        "question": "Therefore a lion from the forest shall strike them down; a wolf from the desert shall devastate them. A leopard is watching their cities; everyone who goes out of them shall be torn in pieces, because their transgressions are many, their apostasies are great. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 5:6",
        "rank": "3,384"
    },
    {
        "question": "Then the LORD said to me, \u201cYou have seen well, for I am watching over my word to perform it.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 1:12",
        "rank": "3,399"
    },
    {
        "question": "I know, O LORD, that the way of man is not in himself, that it is not in man who walks to direct his steps. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 10:23",
        "rank": "3,417"
    },
    {
        "question": "Then the LORD said to me, \u201cOut of the north disaster(1) shall be let loose upon all the inhabitants of the land. Footnotes (1) 1:14 The Hebrew word can mean *evil*, *harm*, or *disaster*, depending on the context; so throughout Jeremiah (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 1:14",
        "rank": "3,493"
    },
    {
        "question": "Declare in Judah, and proclaim in Jerusalem, and say, \u201cBlow the trumpet through the land; cry aloud and say, \u2018Assemble, and let us go into the fortified cities!\u2019 (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 4:5",
        "rank": "3,518"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cI will take up weeping and wailing for the mountains, and a lamentation for the pastures of the wilderness, because they are laid waste so that no one passes through, and the lowing of cattle is not heard; both the birds of the air and the beasts have fled and are gone. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 9:10",
        "rank": "3,601"
    },
    {
        "question": "And I, behold, I make you this day a fortified city, an iron pillar, and bronze walls, against the whole land, against the kings of Judah, its officials, its priests, and the people of the land. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 1:18",
        "rank": "3,605"
    },
    {
        "question": "As a well keeps its water fresh, so she keeps fresh her evil; violence and destruction are heard within her; sickness and wounds are ever before me. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 6:7",
        "rank": "3,672"
    },
    {
        "question": "For behold, I am calling all the tribes of the kingdoms of the north, declares the LORD, and they shall come, and every one shall set his throne at the entrance of the gates of Jerusalem, against all its walls all around and against all the cities of Judah. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 1:15",
        "rank": "3,673"
    },
    {
        "question": "Will you steal, murder, commit adultery, swear falsely, make offerings to Baal, and go after other gods that you have not known, (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 7:9",
        "rank": "3,676"
    },
    {
        "question": "They will fight against you, but they shall not prevail against you, for I am with you, declares the LORD, to deliver you.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 1:19",
        "rank": "3,707"
    },
    {
        "question": "And I will declare my judgments against them, for all their evil in forsaking me. They have made offerings to other gods and worshiped the works of their own hands. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 1:16",
        "rank": "3,804"
    },
    {
        "question": "But you, dress yourself for work;(1) arise, and say to them everything that I command you. Do not be dismayed by them, lest I dismay you before them. Footnotes (1) 1:17 Hebrew *gird up your loins* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 1:17",
        "rank": "3,827"
    },
    {
        "question": "will he be angry forever, will he be indignant to the end?\u2019 Behold, you have spoken, but you have done all the evil that you could.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 3:5",
        "rank": "3,845"
    },
    {
        "question": "The wise men shall be put to shame; they shall be dismayed and taken; behold, they have rejected the word of the LORD, so what wisdom is in them? (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 8:9",
        "rank": "4,212"
    },
    {
        "question": "Raise a standard toward Zion, flee for safety, stay not, for I bring disaster from the north, and great destruction. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 4:6",
        "rank": "4,225"
    },
    {
        "question": "I have heard what the prophets have said who prophesy lies in my name, saying, \u2018I have dreamed, I have dreamed!\u2019 (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 23:25",
        "rank": "4,286"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cHow can I pardon you? Your children have forsaken me and have sworn by those who are no gods. When I fed them to the full, they committed adultery and trooped to the houses of whores. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 5:7",
        "rank": "4,411"
    },
    {
        "question": "Every man is stupid and without knowledge; every goldsmith is put to shame by his idols, for his images are false, and there is no breath in them. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 10:14",
        "rank": "4,420"
    },
    {
        "question": "Therefore thus says the LORD concerning the prophets who prophesy in my name although I did not send them, and who say, \u2018Sword and famine shall not come upon this land\u2019: By sword and famine those prophets shall be consumed. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 14:15",
        "rank": "4,427"
    },
    {
        "question": "Thus said the LORD to me: \u201cGo and stand in the People\u2019s Gate, by which the kings of Judah enter and by which they go out, and in all the gates of Jerusalem, (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 17:19",
        "rank": "4,439"
    },
    {
        "question": "They have sown wheat and have reaped thorns; they have tired themselves out but profit nothing. They shall be ashamed of their(1) harvests because of the fierce anger of the LORD.\u201d Footnotes (1) 12:13 Hebrew *your* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 12:13",
        "rank": "4,472"
    },
    {
        "question": "I will make Jerusalem a heap of ruins, a lair of jackals, and I will make the cities of Judah a desolation, without inhabitant.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 9:11",
        "rank": "4,555"
    },
    {
        "question": "Be warned, O Jerusalem, lest I turn from you in disgust, lest I make you a desolation, an uninhabited land.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 6:8",
        "rank": "4,650"
    },
    {
        "question": "Then the cities of Judah and the inhabitants of Jerusalem will go and cry to the gods to whom they make offerings, but they cannot save them in the time of their trouble. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 11:12",
        "rank": "4,660"
    },
    {
        "question": "When he utters his voice, there is a tumult of waters in the heavens, and he makes the mist rise from the ends of the earth. He makes lightning for the rain, and he brings forth the wind from his storehouses. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 10:13",
        "rank": "4,679"
    },
    {
        "question": "Go now to my place that was in Shiloh, where I made my name dwell at first, and see what I did to it because of the evil of my people Israel. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 7:12",
        "rank": "4,682"
    },
    {
        "question": "all the kings of the north, far and near, one after another, and all the kingdoms of the world that are on the face of the earth. And after them the king of Babylon(1) shall drink. Footnotes (1) 25:26 Hebrew *Sheshach*, a code name for Babylon (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 25:26",
        "rank": "4,733"
    },
    {
        "question": "This is what the LORD says: \"What fault did your ancestors find in me, that they strayed so far from me? They followed worthless idols and became worthless themselves.\"",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 2:5",
        "rank": "4,758"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the reign of King Josiah, the LORD said to me, \"Have you seen what faithless Israel has done? She has gone up on every high hill and under every spreading tree and has committed adultery there.\"",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 3:6",
        "rank": "4,806"
    },
    {
        "question": "My eyes are on all their ways; they are not hidden from me, nor is their sin concealed from my eyes.",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 16:17",
        "rank": "4,860"
    },
    {
        "question": "And then come and stand before me in this house, which bears my Name, and say, \"We are safe\" \u2013 safe to do all these detestable things?",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 7:10",
        "rank": "4,884"
    },
    {
        "question": "They are well-fed, lusty stallions, each neighing for another man's wife.",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 5:8",
        "rank": "4,926"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"I will smash them one against the other, parents and children alike, declares the LORD. I will allow no pity or mercy or compassion to keep me from destroying them.\"",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 13:14",
        "rank": "4,932"
    },
    {
        "question": "A lion has come out of his lair; a destroyer of nations has set out. He has left his place to lay waste your land. Your towns will lie in ruins without inhabitant.",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 4:7",
        "rank": "4,946"
    },
    {
        "question": "He who is the Portion of Jacob is not like these, for he is the Maker of all things, including Israel, the tribe of his inheritance \u2013  the LORD Almighty is his name.",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 10:16",
        "rank": "5,031"
    },
    {
        "question": "This is what the LORD says: \"As for all my wicked neighbors who seize the inheritance I gave my people Israel, I will uproot them from their lands and I will uproot the house of Judah from among them.\"",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 12:14",
        "rank": "5,191"
    },
    {
        "question": "They did not ask, 'Where is the LORD, who brought us up out of Egypt and led us through the barren wilderness, through a land of deserts and ravines, a land of drought and utter darkness, a land where no one travels and no one lives?'",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 2:6",
        "rank": "5,202"
    },
    {
        "question": "Gather up your bundle from the ground, O you who dwell under siege! (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 10:17",
        "rank": "5,213"
    },
    {
        "question": "Has this house, which is called by my name, become a den of robbers in your eyes? Behold, I myself have seen it, declares the LORD. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 7:11",
        "rank": "5,236"
    },
    {
        "question": "and say: \u2018Hear the word of the LORD, you kings of Judah, and all Judah, and all the inhabitants of Jerusalem, who enter by these gates. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 17:20",
        "rank": "5,278"
    },
    {
        "question": "For thus says the LORD: \u201cBehold, I am slinging out the inhabitants of the land at this time, and I will bring distress on them, that they may feel it.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 10:18",
        "rank": "5,297"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hear me, O LORD, and listen to the voice of my adversaries. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 18:19",
        "rank": "5,338"
    },
    {
        "question": "I did not sit in the company of revelers, nor did I rejoice; I sat alone, because your hand was upon me, for you had filled me with indignation. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 15:17",
        "rank": "5,390"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cSend to all the exiles, saying, \u2018Thus says the LORD concerning Shemaiah of Nehelam: Because Shemaiah had prophesied to you when I did not send him, and has made you trust in a lie, (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 29:31",
        "rank": "5,470"
    },
    {
        "question": "She saw that for all the adulteries of that faithless one, Israel, I had sent her away with a decree of divorce. Yet her treacherous sister Judah did not fear, but she too went and played the whore. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 3:8",
        "rank": "5,533"
    },
    {
        "question": "And the people to whom they prophesy shall be cast out in the streets of Jerusalem, victims of famine and sword, with none to bury them\u2014them, their wives, their sons, and their daughters. For I will pour out their evil upon them. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 14:16",
        "rank": "5,615"
    },
    {
        "question": "And I thought, \u2018After she has done all this she will return to me,\u2019 but she did not return, and her treacherous sister Judah saw it. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 3:7",
        "rank": "5,633"
    },
    {
        "question": "Thus says the LORD of hosts: \u201cThey shall glean thoroughly as a vine the remnant of Israel; like a grape gatherer pass your hand again over its branches.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 6:9",
        "rank": "5,712"
    },
    {
        "question": "O inhabitant of Lebanon, nested among the cedars, how you will be pitied when pangs come upon you, pain as of a woman in labor!\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 22:23",
        "rank": "5,723"
    },
    {
        "question": "And I brought you into a plentiful land to enjoy its fruits and its good things. But when you came in, you defiled my land and made my heritage an abomination. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 2:7",
        "rank": "5,741"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cGo up through her vine rows and destroy, but make not a full end; strip away her branches, for they are not the LORD\u2019s. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 5:10",
        "rank": "5,766"
    },
    {
        "question": "Then the word of the LORD came to Jeremiah: (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 29:30",
        "rank": "5,795"
    },
    {
        "question": "Therefore I will give their wives to others and their fields to conquerors, because from the least to the greatest everyone is greedy for unjust gain; from prophet to priest, everyone deals falsely. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 8:10",
        "rank": "5,803"
    },
    {
        "question": "But if any nation will not listen, then I will utterly pluck it up and destroy it, declares the LORD.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 12:17",
        "rank": "5,837"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cTherefore do not pray for this people, or lift up a cry or prayer on their behalf, for I will not listen when they call to me in the time of their trouble. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 11:14",
        "rank": "5,865"
    },
    {
        "question": "And now, because you have done all these things, declares the LORD, and when I spoke to you persistently you did not listen, and when I called you, you did not answer, (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 7:13",
        "rank": "5,866"
    },
    {
        "question": "And it shall come to pass, if they will diligently learn the ways of my people, to swear by my name, \u2018As the LORD lives,\u2019 even as they taught my people to swear by Baal, then they shall be built up in the midst of my people. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 12:16",
        "rank": "5,908"
    },
    {
        "question": "But first I will doubly repay their iniquity and their sin, because they have polluted my land with the carcasses of their detestable idols, and have filled my inheritance with their abominations.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 16:18",
        "rank": "5,919"
    },
    {
        "question": "The priests did not say, \u2018Where is the LORD?\u2019 Those who handle the law did not know me; the shepherds(1) transgressed against me; the prophets prophesied by Baal and went after things that do not profit. Footnotes (1) 2:8 Or *rulers* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 2:8",
        "rank": "5,940"
    },
    {
        "question": "For this put on sackcloth, lament and wail, for the fierce anger of the LORD has not turned back from us.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 4:8",
        "rank": "6,008"
    },
    {
        "question": "For your gods have become as many as your cities, O Judah, and as many as the streets of Jerusalem are the altars you have set up to shame, altars to make offerings to Baal. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 11:13",
        "rank": "6,111"
    },
    {
        "question": "My tent is destroyed, and all my cords are broken; my children have gone from me, and they are not; there is no one to spread my tent again and to set up my curtains. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 10:20",
        "rank": "6,112"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the man so wise that he can understand this? To whom has the mouth of the LORD spoken, that he may declare it? Why is the land ruined and laid waste like a wilderness, so that no one passes through? (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 9:12",
        "rank": "6,113"
    },
    {
        "question": "For cross to the coasts of Cyprus and see, or send to Kedar and examine with care; see if there has been such a thing. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 2:10",
        "rank": "6,137"
    },
    {
        "question": "Because she took her whoredom lightly, she polluted the land, committing adultery with stone and tree. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 3:9",
        "rank": "6,200"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long shall there be lies in the heart of the prophets who prophesy lies, and who prophesy the deceit of their own heart, (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 23:26",
        "rank": "6,214"
    },
    {
        "question": "To whom shall I speak and give warning, that they may hear? Behold, their ears are uncircumcised, they cannot listen; behold, the word of the LORD is to them an object of scorn; they take no pleasure in it. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Jeremiah 6:10",
        "rank": "6,326"
    }
]